telestream.net 2018-10-16

# Telestream Company - Privacy Policy

## Telestream Privacy Policy

Effective Date: May 25, 2018 

Telestream, LLC ("Telestream") values your privacy. . In this Privacy Policy ("Policy"), we describe how we collect, use, and disclose information that we obtain about visitors to our websites including, but not limited to, telestream.net, pandastream.com, gameshow.net, and subdomains, (collectively, the "Site”) and the services available through our Site, and data collected offline from European Union persons using our products and services (collectively, the "Services").

By visiting the Site, or using any of our Services, you acknowledge that your personal information will be handled as described in this Policy. Your use of our Site or Services, and any dispute over privacy, is subject to this Policy.

The information we collect through the Site and Services is controlled by Telestream LLC, which is headquartered in the United States at 848 Gold Flat Road, Nevada City, California 95959, USA. If you contract with one of our EU affiliated entities, then that entity also will be a controller of your data.

  * What Information Do We Collect About You and Why?
  * Information We Collect Directly From You
  * Information We Collect Automatically
  * How We Use Your Information
  * How We Share Your Information
  * Our Use of Cookies and Other Tracking Mechanisms
  * Third-Party Analytics
  * Third-Party Ad Networks
  * User Generated Content
  * Third-Party Links
  * Security of My Personal Information
  * Access To My Personal Information
  * What Choices Do I Have Regarding Use of My Personal Information?
  * Children Under 13
  * Information for EU Individuals
  * Contact Us
  * Changes to this Policy

## What Information Do We Collect About You and Why?

We may collect information about you directly from you and from third parties, as well as automatically through your use of our Site or Services.

## Information We Collect Directly From You

Certain areas and features of our Site and Services require registration and/or creation of a user account. Depending on what area of our Site or Services you register for, you will be required to provide some or all of the following information: your company name, name, address, phone number, email, username, and password. We also may collect additional optional information from you, including information about what products you are interested in, your software version, CPU type, OS version, other system specific data, website URL, and signature information. If you choose to purchase a product you will need to provide your financial information to our payment processors, Avangate and FastSpring; any such information will be governed by the [Avangate](http://www.avangate.com/privacy.php) and [FastSpring](https://fastspring.com/privacy/) privacy policies.

## Information We Collect Automatically

We may automatically collect the following information about your use of our Site or Services through cookies, web beacons, and other technologies: your domain name; your browser type and operating system; web pages you view; links you click; your IP address; the length of time you visit our Site and/or use our Services; your device ID; and the referring URL, or the webpage that led you to our Site. We may combine this information with other information that we have collected about you, including, where applicable, your user name, name, and other personal information. Please see the section Cookies and Other Tracking Mechanisms below for more information.

## How We Use Your Information

We use your information, including your personal information, for the following purposes:

  * To provide our Services to you, to communicate with you about your use of our Services, to respond to your inquiries, to fulfill your orders, and for other customer service purposes.
  * To tailor the content and information that we may send or display to you, to offer location customization, and personalized help and instructions, and to otherwise personalize your experiences while using the Site or our Services.
  * For marketing and promotional purposes. For example, we may use your information, such as your email address, to send you news and newsletters, special offers, and promotions, or to otherwise contact you about products or information we think may interest you. We also may use the information that we learn about you to assist us in advertising our Services on third party websites.
  * To better understand how users access and use our Site and Services, both on an aggregated and individualized basis, in order to improve our Site and Services and respond to user desires and preferences, and for other research and analytical purposes.
  * To administer surveys and questionnaires.
  * To administer our corporate customer contracts. For example, we will use a customer’s employee’s contact information to send our invoices or to send service communications to.
  * To comply with applicable legal or regulatory obligations, including as part of a judicial proceeding; to respond to a subpoena, warrant, court order, or other legal process; or as part of an investigation or request, whether formal or informal, from law enforcement or a governmental authority
  * To protect the safety, rights, property, or security of Telestream, our services, any third party, or the general public; to detect, prevent, or otherwise address fraud, security, or technical issues; to prevent or stop activity that Telestream, in its sole discretion, may consider to be, or to pose a risk of being, an illegal, unethical, or legally actionable activity; to use as evidence in litigation; to conduct audits; and to enforce this Policy or our Terms of Service.

## How We Share Your Information

We may share your information, including personal information, as follows:

  * Telestream Users. Your user name and any information that you post to any area on our Site, including, without limitation, reviews, comments, and text will be available to, and searchable by, all users of that area of our Site.
  * Affiliates. We may disclose the information we collect from you to our affiliates or subsidiaries; however, if we do so, their use and disclosure of your personally identifiable information will be subject to this Policy.
  * Service Providers. We may disclose the information we collect from you to third party vendors, service providers, contractors or agents who perform functions on our behalf.
  * Business Transfers. If we are acquired by or merged with another company, if substantially all of our assets are transferred to another company, or as part of a bankruptcy proceeding, we may transfer the information we have collected from you to the other company.
  * In Response to Legal Process. We also may disclose the information we collect from you in order to comply with the law, a judicial proceeding, court order, or other legal process, such as in response to a court order or a subpoena.
  * To Protect Us and Others. We also may disclose the information we collect from you where we believe it is necessary to investigate, prevent, or take action regarding illegal activities, suspected fraud, situations involving potential threats to the safety of any person, violations of our Terms of Service or this Policy, or as evidence in litigation in which Telestream is involved.
  * Aggregate and De-Identified Information. We may share aggregate or de-identified information about users with third parties for marketing, advertising, research or similar purposes.

We do not disclose or transfer your personal information to non-affiliated third parties for direct marketing purposes without your prior written consent.

## Our Use of Cookies and Other Tracking Mechanisms

For information on our use of cookies and other tracking mechanisms, please refer to our Cookie Information web page (click here).

## Third Party Analytics

We use automated devices and applications, such as Google Analytics, to evaluate usage of our Site. We also may use other analytic means to evaluate our Services. We use these tools to help us improve our Services, performance, and user experiences. These entities may use cookies and other tracking technologies to perform their services. We do not share your personal information with these third parties. To learn more about Google’s privacy practices, please review the Google Privacy Policy at https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/. You can also download the Google Analytics Opt-out Browser Add-on to prevent their data from being used by Google Analytics at https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout.

## Emails and Newsletters

Emails we send you may include a tag that notifies us whether you have received or opened the email, or clicked a link within the email. If you do not want us to collect this information, you can opt out of receiving emails from use (links in the emails provide opt out options).

## Third-Party Ad Networks

We sometimes work with other third-party companies who use tracking technologies to serve ads on our behalf across the Internet. These companies may collect information about your online interaction with us, including advertising. Network advertisers are third parties that display advertisements based on your visits to our Site as well as other websites. This enables us and these third parties to target advertisements by displaying ads for products and services in which you might be interested. Third party ad network providers, advertisers, sponsors and/or traffic measurement services may use cookies, JavaScript, web beacons (including clear GIFs), Flash LSOs and other technologies to measure the effectiveness of their ads and to personalize advertising content to you. These third party cookies and other technologies are governed by each third partys specific privacy policy, not this one. We may provide these third-party advertisers with information about your usage of our Site and our services, as well as aggregate or non-personally identifiable information about visitors to our Site and users of our service.

**Third-Party Ad Networks.** We use third parties such as network advertisers to serve advertisements on third-party websites or other media (e.g., social networking platforms). This enables us and these third parties to target advertisements to you for products and services in which you might be interested. Third-party ad network providers, advertisers, sponsors and/or traffic measurement services may use cookies, JavaScript, web beacons (including clear GIFs), Flash LSOs and other tracking technologies to measure the effectiveness of their ads and to personalize advertising content to you. These third-party cookies and other technologies are governed by each third party’s specific privacy policy, not this one. We may provide these third-party advertisers with information, including personal information, about you.

Users in the United States may opt out of many third-party ad networks. For example, you may go to the Digital Advertising Alliance (“DAA”) Consumer Choice Page for information about opting out of interest-based advertising and their choices regarding having information used by DAA companies. You may also go to the Network Advertising Initiative (“NAI”) Consumer Opt-Out Page for information about opting out of interest-based advertising and their choices regarding having information used by NAI members. If you are a user in the European Union, you may opt-out of certain third party cookies that we and other websites may use for targeted advertising through the European Interactive Digital Advertising Alliance (EDAA) Your Online Choices Page or www.aboutads.info.

Opting out from one or more companies listed on the DAA Consumer Choice Page, the NAI Consumer Opt-Out Page, or the EDAA Your Online Choices Page will opt you out from those companies’ delivery of interest-based content or ads to you, but it does not mean you will no longer receive any advertising through our Site or on other websites. You may continue to receive advertisements, for example, based on the particular website that you are viewing (i.e., contextually based ads). Also, if your browsers are configured to reject cookies when you opt out on the DAA, NAI, or EDAA websites, your opt out may not be effective. Additional information is available on the DAA’s website at www.aboutads.info or the NAI’s website at www.networkadvertising.org.

## User Generated Content

We invite you to post content on our Site (where applicable), including your comments, pictures, and any other information that you would like to be available on our Site. If you post content to publicly available areas of our Site, all of the information that you post will be available to all visitors to our Site users. If you post content to areas that require a log-in, all of the information that you post will be available to registered users of that area. If you post your own content on our Site or Services, your posting may become public and Telestream cannot prevent such information from being used in a manner that may violate this Policy, the law, or your personal privacy.

## Third-Party Links

Our Site and Services may contain links to third-party websites. Any access to and use of such linked websites is not governed by this Policy, but instead is governed by the privacy policies of those third party websites. We are not responsible for the information practices of such third party websites.

## Security of My Personal Information

We have implemented commercially reasonable precautions to protect the information we collect from loss, misuse, and unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration, and destruction. Please be aware that despite our best efforts, no data security measures can guarantee 100% security.

You should take steps to protect against unauthorized access to your password, phone, and computer by, among other things, signing off after using a shared computer, choosing a robust password that nobody else knows or can easily guess, and keeping your user name and password private. We are not responsible for any lost, stolen, or compromised passwords or for any activity on your account via unauthorized password activity.

## Access To My Personal Information

You may modify personal information that you have submitted by logging into your account and updating your information or by contacting us using the contact information provided below. Please note that copies of information that you have updated, modified, or deleted may remain viewable in cached and archived pages of the Site for a period of time.

If you are a resident of the European Union, please see the Information for EU Individuals section below for additional information on accessing your information and other legal rights available to you under European Union law.

## What Choices Do I Have Regarding Use of My Personal Information?

We may send periodic promotional or informational emails to you. You may opt-out of such communications by following the opt-out instructions contained in the email. Please note that it may take up to 10 business days for us to process opt-out requests. If you opt-out of receiving emails about recommendations or other information we think may interest you, we may still send you emails about your account or any Services you have requested or received from us.

## Children Under 13

Our Services are not designed for children under 13. If we discover that a child under 13 has provided us with personal information, we will delete such information from our systems.

## Information for EU Individuals

_When we act as Data Controller:_ If we process your personal information in our capacity as a data controller, the following applies: 

We collect, use, and share your personal information where we are satisfied that we have an appropriate legal basis to do this. This may be because:

  * Our use of your personal information is necessary to perform a contract or take steps to enter into a contract with you (for example when you choose to purchase software from us); or
  * Our use of your personal information is in our legitimate interest as a commercial organization (for example in order to make improvements to our products and services and to provide you with information you request); you have a right to object to processing as explained in the section below titled Your Legal Rights;
  * Our use of your personal information is necessary to comply with a relevant legal or regulatory obligation that we have (for example, where we are required to disclose personal information to a court); or
  * Our use of your personal information is in accordance with your consent (for example, when your consent to the receipt of marketing communications is required by local law.

If you would like to find out more about the legal bases on which we process personal information, please contact us using the details below.

**Your Legal Rights.** Subject to certain exemptions, and in some cases dependent upon the processing activity we are undertaking, European Union individuals have certain rights in relation to your personal information:

_Right to access, correct, and delete your personal information:_ You have the right to request access to the personal information that we hold about you and:(a) the source of your personal information; (b) the purposes, legal basis and methods of processing; (c) the data controller’s identity; and (d) the entities or categories of entities to whom your personal information may be transferred.

You also have the right to request that we delete your information. 

We are not required to comply with your request to erase personal information if the processing of your personal information is necessary for compliance with a legal obligation or for the establishment, exercise, or deference of legal claims. 

_Right to restrict the processing of your personal information:_ You have the right to restrict the use of your personal information when (i) you contest the accuracy of the data; (ii) the use is unlawful but you do not want us to erase the data; (iii) we no longer need the personal information for the relevant purposes, but we require it for the establishment, exercise, or defense of legal claims; or (iv) you have objected to our personal information use justified on our legitimate interests verification as to whether we have a compelling interest to continue to use your data. 

We can continue to use your personal information following a request for restriction, where:

  * we have your consent; or
  * to establish, exercise or defend legal claims; or
  * to protect the rights of another natural or legal person. 

_Right to data portability:_ To the extent that we process your information (i) based on your consent or under a contract; and (ii) through automated means, you have the right to receive such personal information in a structured, commonly used, machine-readable format, or you can ask to have it transferred directly to another data controller. 

_Right to object to the processing of your personal information:_ You can object to any processing of your personal information which has our legitimate interests as its legal basis, if you believe your fundamental rights and freedoms outweigh our legitimate interests. If you raise an objection, we have an opportunity to demonstrate that we have compelling legitimate interests which override your rights and freedoms. 

_Right to obtain a copy of personal information safeguards used for transfers outside your jurisdiction:_ You can ask to obtain a copy of, or reference to, the safeguards under which your personal information is transferred outside of the EEA. 

_Right to lodge a complaint with your local supervisory authority:_ You have a right to lodge a complaint with your local supervisory authority if you have concerns about how we are processing your personal information. 

We ask that you please attempt to resolve any issues with us first, although you have a right to contact your supervisory authority at any time. 

_How to Exercise Your Rights:_ If you would like to exercise any of the rights described above, please send us a request to gdpr@telestream.net. In your message, please indicate the right you would like to exercise and the information that you would like to access, review, correct, or delete. 

We may ask you for additional information to confirm your identity and for security purposes, before disclosing the personal information requested to you. We reserve the right to charge a fee where permitted by law, for instance if your request is manifestly unfounded or excessive. We may not always be able to fully address your request, for example if it would impact the duty of confidentiality we owe to others, or if we are legally entitled to deal with the request in a different way.

_If we process your information as a Data Processor:_ For certain activities where we provide services to our customers, we act only on the instruction of those corporate customers. In those situations, the corporate customer is the Data Controller for that purpose. Where we process your data in our capacity as a data processor on behalf of the Data Controller, the processing of your data will not be governed by this Policy, but you can contact the customer directly to learn about their processing of your information and to exercise your rights, or we will forward your request directly to our corporate customers.

**Cross-border Transfer of Information.** Telestream generally maintains servers and systems in the United States hosted by third party service providers. We also may subcontract the processing of your data to, or otherwise share your data with, other third parties in the United States or countries other than your country of residence. As a result, where the personal information that we collect through the Site, Services, or in connection with providing services to or administering our relationship with a corporate customer is transferred to and processed in the United States or anywhere else outside the European Economic Area (EEA) for the purposes described above, we will take steps to ensure that the information receives the same level of protection as if it remained within the EEA, including entering into data transfer agreements, using the EU Commission approved Standard Contractual Clauses, or by relying on certification schemes such as the EU - US Privacy Shield. You have a right to details of the mechanisms under which your data is transferred outside the EEA. 

## Contact Us

If you have questions about the privacy aspects of our Services or would like to make a complaint, please contact us using the Opt-out Links on our emails and newsletters or in any of the following ways.

Telephone:  530-470-1300

Fax:  530-470-1301

Email:  [ info@telestream.net](mailto:info@telestream.net)

## Changes to this Policy

This Policy is current as of the Effective Date set forth above. We may change this Policy from time to time, so please be sure to check back periodically. We will post any changes to this Policy on our Site. If we make any changes to this Policy that materially affect our practices with regard to the personal information we have previously collected from you, we will endeavor to provide you with notice in advance of such change by highlighting the change on our Site.

If you own a Telestream product, visit our Support Center for the latest software updates and product information.
